Haru-kun, I don't want you to go!
Ayase Miharu was
Amakawa Haruto's childhood friend.
Mii-chan, don't cry.
We'll see each other again, okay?
They lived in two apartments
next to each other.
I hate this! Don't go, Haru-kun!
They were always together...
Please. Why? Why are you...
until Haruto's parents divorced
and he had to move away,
When I grow up, I'll come and get you!
Which is why, when they parted,
they were already very special to each other.
So... So, when I do, let's get married!
That way we can always be
together, side by side.
I'll do it! I will! Haru-kun, I'll marry you!
That's the promise they made each other.
Inaba University's Affiliate High School
Entrance Ceremony
And so he worked diligently at his studies.
There was a famous school in the
town where he and Miharu had lived,
and he worked very hard
in order to enroll there.
Inaba High
Hardball Baseball
Chemistry Club
New Members
Inquire Here!
I don't have time to join a club.
I really pushed my father to let me
come back to this neighborhood.
Part-Time Work Permission Form
I have to earn money for
my living expenses myself.
Mii-chan?
Hey, Miharu!
Oh! Takahisa-kun!
Did I keep you waiting?
No, I only just got here.
Really? Well, let's go.
A moment please, Takahisa-kun?
Have you forgotten that
you came here with me?
S-Satsuki-san! No, of course I haven't.
The moment you spotted Miharu-chan,
you ran off on your own.
You're no different than
you were in middle school.
We're keeping Aki and Masato
waiting. We should go.
Oh! Oniichan!
Aki!
It's been a while, Satsuki-neechan!
We haven't seen you lately, Satsuki-san.
Yes, and you've both grown so much!
Satsuki-neechan, you've
gotten even more beautiful!
You say the nicest things, Masato-kun!
Okay, as I am your senpai,
today, it's my treat!
Miharu-chan and Takahisa-kun
have entered high school.
Aki-chan has entered middle school.
And Masato-kun has moved up to sixth grade.
In honor of all of that...
Let's have a huge celebration!
Wow, that's awesome! Yay!
Thank you, Satsuki-neechan!
Y-You should show a little more restraint.
Onii—
Aishia?
Haruto, please, help them!
What?
Spirit Chronicles 2
Rio?
J-Just what do you two think you're doing?!
When I Met You in This World, You Were...
Masato, where are we?
Don't ask me.
W-Well, why don't we try to
figure out what this place is?
No Service
No service?
Is this the right direction, Aishia?
Yes. Keep going southeast.
What's this? Did someone
use spatial magic?
This is...
What's going on?
No!
Let go!
No, stop!
What're you doing? Stop! Aki-neechan!
Please! Please let them go.
I'm begging you!
I don't understand what you're saying.
Come on!
You're over here.
Stop this!
What are you planning to
do with Miharu-oneechan?
Miharu-oneechan!
Silence! Keep quiet!
A-Aki-neechan, I think maybe
we shouldn't make a fuss.
What are you saying?
Smoke?
Is someone over there?
Huh? What is it? What's going on?
I'm looking for the person who dropped this.
Do you happen to know anything about it?
What's that? Never seen it before.
Starting a fight in this situation
wouldn't be a smart idea.
I see. Sorry to have bothered you.
Help! Please, help us!
Stop it! Keep quiet!
Neechan! Aki-neechan, are you okay?
Japanese?
Our newest merchandise is
a little noisy, that's all.
The children who just spoke
are the ones I'm looking for.
I heard one of them asking for help.
Exactly what is going on here?
You understand their language?
Kill him!
Hey! Time to get to work!
Their movements are well-organized.
They're used to fighting as a group.
Looks like you mistook
recklessness for courage.
If you want a fight, then I won't hold back.
Photon Bullet!
I wanted to take their leader hostage
and conduct negotiations quickly,
but it seems things won't be that simple.
I have no choice.
You fool!
Fireball!
Gah!
Release the children you've abducted.
The others won't make a move
without your order, am I right?
Do it now!
Release them! Hurry!
Are you all right?
Y-You understand Japanese?
I do, but... I'll explain later.
Are you the only ones who were captured?
Th-There's one more.
They put her in that wagon over there.
I came to help. Are you all right?
How?
Why are you...
Spirit Chronicles 2
here in this place?
Aishia.
I think I've saved the people
you were talking about.
Let's meet up before sundown.
Can you tell where I am?
Yes, I can. I'll bring Celia with me.
Thank you.
It's beautiful!
U-Um, I'm sorry.
May I speak with you a moment?
What is it?
Thank you so much for saving us.
If you hadn't come, I don't know
what would have happened to us.
No, I only did what needed to be done.
And there was something
I wanted to ask you, too.
Something you wanted to ask?
Uh, I mean...
My name is Ayase Miharu.
May I ask what your name is?
Name? My name is...
I'm in the middle of a certain situation,
so I'm currently going by the name Haruto.
I don't have a family name.
Haruto?
Aki-chan.
Aki?
Haruto had a sister three
years younger than himself.
He never saw her again after that, but...
Is this girl her?
There is a certain resemblance...
but what's more, Mii-chan... or rather, Miharu-san
called her "Aki." That's pretty conclusive.
Um, I...
Oh, sorry.
I was just wondering if there was
something wrong with my name.
I'm sorry. It's nothing.
Hey, Haruto-niichan? What did you mean when
you said you don't have a family name?
Oh, I'm Sendo Masato.
I'm Aki-neechan's little brother.
Amakawa Haruto didn't have a younger brother.
And he doesn't carry the Amakawa family name.
If he's Aki's little brother, then perhaps...
Haruto's mother remarried?
Her little brother.
Then, would Aki-chan's
full name be Sendo Aki?
Oh! Yes, that's right.
I'm sorry for not introducing myself.
Not at all. You were asking why
I don't have a family name, weren't you?
The sun is about to set.
This story is likely to be a long one,
so why don't we go somewhere else?
I'll prepare a spot that's more comfortable.
This way, please.
This seems like a good spot.
Discharge.
Wh-What is that?
It looks like it's just a boulder,
but there's a living space inside.
This way, please.
Rio!
Th-They're flying!
Are you all right? You're not hurt?
Yes, I'm fine, Celia.
I'm so glad.
You're the ones Aishia was
talking about, aren't you?
You saved them!
Yes. This is Miss Ayase Miharu,
Miss Sendo Aki, and her younger
brother, Master Sendo Masato.
I see. I'm Celia, Celia Claire.
Pleased to meet you.
This is Professor Celia. She was
my teacher and I owe her a lot.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
My name is Ayase Miharu.
Um...
They don't speak Strahlian.
Oh, I see.
Celia?
What are you doing?
Aishia, what are you doing?
What? Why...
Strahlian?
I formed a temporary path between you two.
For the present, I can interpret for you.
Aishia... You can do that?
I can do it because you understand
the languages, Haruto.
If you don't, then I can't.
I see.
Haruto, I'm hungry.
Oh. Yes, you're right.
Everyone, please come inside.
Oh, it's lovely!
It's so big!
Even better than the size, this place has a bath.
Please feel free to make use of it.
There's a bath here? Yay!
Masato! You're getting way too excited.
Then Haruto-san's name is
actually Rio-san, is that right?
And Aishia-san is Rio-san's bond spirit?
Yes, that's what they told me.
Though, I've only just met Aishia today,
so I don't know any of the details.
Pardon me for joining you.
Miharu-oneechan, what were you talking about?
She said that Aishia-san isn't
a human. She's a spirit.
What? A-A spirit?!
So that's why she can do
simultaneous interpretation!
Y-Yes, probably.
So, basically, we came
to a fantasy RPG world?
I didn't really play many games like
that in my last life, so I'm not sure,
but I think that sounds about right.
It's just that, unlike a game,
there's no reset button here.
Oh. So if you hadn't shown up, Rio-niichan,
things would've been really bad for us?
Yes. You would have become slaves.
I see.
The bath was wonderful!
Thank you, Haruto-san.
I'm glad to hear it.
Rio, I hadn't used a bath like that before,
but it felt amazing and I had a lot of fun!
Rio, why don't you take one, too?
No, I'll take one after we eat.
What are those clothes?
Aki lent them to me.
She said it would be odd to change back
into a wedding dress after our bath.
I see.
These clothes are so easy to move in and so
nice against the skin. They surprised me!
I've never seen this fabric before.
I just bought these for my
school's entrance ceremony today,
so they aren't dirty or anything.
I think they should be all right.
I see. She says that she
likes them very much.
But if none of you have a
change of clothes later,
that will cause problems, won't it?
Tomorrow, let's go and buy
some daily necessities.
Oh, but we don't have any money.
Don't worry. I can manage the
cost of some everyday items.
But Rio, where will you go to buy them?
What do you think of going to Amande?
Amande! Then, do you think we could
exchange my wedding dress for money, too?
You really don't need to worry about money.
Please rest easy on that account.
Now, why don't we go and eat?
Yes, you're right.
My! Rio, did you make all of this?
Yes.
Now, everyone, let's eat.
I see.
Piecing all of your accounts together,
it sounds like you got caught up in a
phenomenon caused by summoning magic.
That's likely how you came to this world.
Will it be impossible for
us to return to Earth?
I don't know the answer to that.
The situation is too different from
my being reborn into this world.
Haruto-san, you died in a traffic
accident as a university student.
Then, those memories came back to
you as a child in this world, right?
Yes, which is why I don't think my
experience will be of much help to you.
Rio, may I speak, too?
Yes, of course.
Given all of your accounts,
those six pillars of light we saw,
and the events of this year,
Year 1,000 of the Holy Era,
this may all have something to do
with the legend of the Six Wise Gods.
Yes, I had the same thought.
A thousand years after the Divine-Demon War,
six sacred stones will glow
in different colors...
and pillars of light will
soar into the heavens.
Heroes clad in powerful and divine raiment
will return from outside of Strahl.
And in place of the six wisest gods,
they shall lead all of humanity.
Still, I can't imagine that these
are the heroes the legend spoke of.
What do you think?
Yes, you're right.
Um...
Yes?
We were with some other people
right before we came to this world.
Satsuki-san and Takahisa-kun. Do you
think they came to this world, too?
I don't know.
I think it's a possibility,
but I can't say for certain.
I see.
You're worried about them, aren't you?
Yes. We were fortunate that you came
to save us, Haruto-san. So we're safe...
but our sense of "normal"
carries no meaning in this world.
Haruto, I'm sleepy. Let's go to bed.
Huh? Wait.
Wait just a minute, Aishia.
I can't take it anymore.
I've used too much power today.
J-Just what do you two think you're doing?!
Replenishing my magic.
No, no, no! You shouldn't be doing that!
Why?
Why? Because...
I always do this. I sleep with Haruto.
What?!
No, Professor, there's a reason for this.
Haruto, let's hurry up and go to bed.
W-Wait right there!
R-Rio hasn't...
Rio hasn't had a bath yet!
What? That's what she's upset about?
E-Excuse me.
We'll tidy up here.
Oh, you don't have to!
Come on, Masato! You help, too!
Huh? Right.
It's all right! Please, just leave it!
Rio!
No, it's really just...
Please, just listen to me!
Next Time
Shopping in Another World
"Shopping in Another World."
Spirit Chronicles 2
It's so long!
Meow.
Illustration: Minazuki Futago